ACWA's Jacob Potofsky Records from the President's Office 5619/010
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACWA's Jacob Potofsky Records from the President's Office
1941-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
Potofsky, Jacob S. (Jacob Samuel), 1894-1979
5619/010
10 cubic feet
10 linear feet
Correspondence, reports, publications.
This collection consists of correspondence, reports, and files from Jacob Potofsky during the time he was president of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and after.
6751665
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
March 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 2011
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related collections: 5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America 5619/004: ACTWU's Jacob Sheinkman Records from the Sectretary-Treasurer's and President's Offices 5619/036: ACTWU's Murray Finley Records from the President's Office And all other 5619 collections.
Textile industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946; AFL-CIO; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Textile Workers Union of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization)
6751665
- David Morse Dinner, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  January 16; location: Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York City
- Speeches- Jacob S. Potofsky, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  a tribute to Franz Daniel
- Speeches- Jacob S. Potofsky, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Special Mail, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Organization of American States (O.A.S) Fourth Technical Seminar on the Development of Workers' Banks, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Caracas, Venezuela; August 5-11
- Speech. Jacob S. Potofsky Dedication Regional Clinic, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Bnei Bank, Israel
- Speeches- Amalgamated Bank 50th Anniversary, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  April 14
- United Housing Foundation Annual Meeting, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  April 7
- "Harry Rogoff- The man- His Ideas- His Life", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Hillel Rogoff Memorial Lecture; December 14
- Geneva, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  June-July 16
- Special Correspondence - Jacob S. Potofsky, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Presidential Inauguration, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Europe Trip, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Re: Patrick Vincent Job Applications, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Replies to incoming letters on retirement, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Organization of American States Conference, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  August 5-11
- Correspondences: Israel, Stockholm, Norway, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  July
- Trips, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Personal File, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  January-June
- Christmas List, 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Personal Notes and Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Special Memos, Correspondences, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Photos, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photographs: Trip to Europe (extras), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Branchville National Bank, 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Branchville National Bank, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Branchville, New Jersey
- Branchville National Bank, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Letters and Memos - Special, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Special Mail, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Mail and Memoranda- Confidential and Special ( 1 of 2), 1941-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Mail and Memoranda- Confidential and Special ( 2 of 2), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence- "The Four Seasons", 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence: Trade Union Congress (TUC), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  England
- Political Speeches, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Speech Program, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Special Account Statements, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Statements: Jacob S. Potofsky, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- European Trip, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  August 17- October 1
- International Labor Organization, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence Re: International Labor Conference, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence Re: International Labor Conference, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  July-December
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  January- June
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Magazine Subscriptions (Personal), 1961-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Financial, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- David A. Morse Tribute Correspondences, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Potofsky's 80th Birthday
- Correspondences, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- World Rehabilitation Fund: David A. Morse Tribute, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Retirement Dinner, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Potofsky and Frank Rosenblum; January 13
- Tripartite Technical Meeting for Clothing Industry (I.L.O Conference), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Location: Geneva; September 21- October 2
- Bank Dinner, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Saturday, April 14
- Speeches, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Executive Board Meeting, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  August 30
- General Executive Board Meeting, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  November 9
- General Executive Board Meeting, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  July 7
- Confidential Material, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Clothing Committee, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  December 16
- Clothing Committee, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Location: Atlantic City; Date: March 25
- Stabilization, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- General Executive Board, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Location: Washington, D.C; November 10-12
- Stabilization, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Interoffice memos to J.S. Potofsky, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Confidential
- Letters and Memos - Confidential, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: General Executive Board Minutes, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Annuity
- Memoranda - Inter Office, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Confidential Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Personal Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Personal Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  July- December
- Personal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Personal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Personal Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- F.E. Compton and Company, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  The Compton Five-Point Educational Program
- Personal Correspondence, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Personal Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Personal Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Personal Correspondence, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Personal Correspondence, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Personal Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Personal Correspondence, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Personal Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Personal Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Personal Correspondence, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Personal Correspondence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Personal Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Personal Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Personal Correspondence, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Personal Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Personal Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Personal Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Personal Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Personal Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clipping "Man in the News", 1972 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  May 3
- Immigration and Biographical Materials (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Obituaries, Notebooks, etc. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Photocopies of newspaper obituaries, correspondence, and two, small, handwritten notebooks
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 1 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Various reports, pamphlets, and personal correspondence.
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 2 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 3 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- American Institute of Men's and Boy's Wear, Incorporated, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Concerning a tribute to Louis C. Pfeifle and a magazine entitled, "Public Relations Exchange". The folder also includes tickets to the tribute dinner and a program for a dinner tribute to Jacob Potofsky.
- American Jewish Committee, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Invitation and recommendations to amend bylaws of the group.
- American Jewish Congress, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Invitations.
- Application, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Job Applications and resumes.
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 1 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Various correspondence, reports, and notes.
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 2 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 3 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Agreements [folder 1 of 3], 1963 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Agreements made in various cities.
- Agreements [folder 2 of 3], 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Agreements [folder 3 of 3], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Atlantic Mills - St. Louis, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Agreement
- Miscellaneous "B" [folder 1 of 2], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Various correspondence, notes, and reports.
- Miscellaneous "B" [folder 2 of 2], 1966 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Brandeis University, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Memorandums, correspondence, and meeting reports.
- Bank-Holding Company Bill [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Correspondence and statements.
- Bank-Holding Company Bill [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Boys' Town, Incorporated, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Correspondence and notes.
- Brandeis University Dinner, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  October 13th, 1996. Notes, correspondence, attendance lists, and participation.
- Jacob Samuel Potofsky Dinner, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Brandeis University. Correspondence, notes, attendance lists, and a university bulletin.
- Sol Brandzel, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  General Correspondence.
- Car Rental, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Hand written request to a car rental company from Daisy C. Pennington asking for tires.
- Chicago Medical School, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Correspondence and bulletins.
- Christmas Gifts, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Note about Christmas.
- City of Hope, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Correspondence regarding gratitude for support, brochures, and receipts.
- Clothing Manufacturers Association, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Memorandums, correspondence, news bulletins, and reports entitled "The Financial Experiences of The Men's and Boys' Coat and Suit Manufacturers" and "Merchandising and sales Trends."
- Clothing Negotiations, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Memos about negotiations.
- Complaints A-M, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Complaints and responses to them.
- Complaints N-Z, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Convention, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  A handwritten letter about gift ideas to give at the convention.
- Contributions Granted [folder 1 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  January through June.
- Contributions Granted [folder 2 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Contributions Denied, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Requests for contributions.
- Contributions Granted [folder 1 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  July through December.
- Contributions Granted [folder 2 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Convention, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Regarding plans for the future meeting. Includes correspondence and brochures.
- Co-op City, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, memos, finance, and newspaper clippings.
- United Housing Foundation, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Notes, correspondence, and reports.
- Curry Auto Rental, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Correspondence.
- Cotton Garment Negotiations, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  Notice of meetings.
- Cotton Garment Negotiations [folder 1 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Cotton Garment Negotiations [folder 2 of 2], 1966 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- American Jewish Committee, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Invitations to a 65th Anniversary Dinner and a "Response to Political Violence Through Democratic Means" conference.
- Miscellaneous "B" [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Various correspondence, memorandums, and press releases from different organizations.
- Miscellaneous "B" [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Boy's Town, Incorporated, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, invitations, and contribution requests.
- Brandeis University, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Correspondence regarding fellows and contributions.
- Sol Brandzel, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Various correspondence.
- Clothing Manufacturers Association, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Press releases, meeting and statement highlights, and memorandums.
- Clothing Negotiations [folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Agreements.
- Clothing Negotiations [folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Clothing Negotiations [folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Various correspondence, memorandums, handwritten notes, and two paperback books.
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous "A" [folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Contributions [folder 1 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Contributions list from January to June.
- Contributions [folder 2 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Correspondence from organizations listed alphabetically "A" to "E".
- Contributions [folder 3 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Correspondence from organizations listed alphabetically "F" to "I".
- Contributions [folder 4 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Correspondence from organizations listed alphabetically "J" to "M".
- Contributions [folder 5 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Correspondence from organizations listed alphabetically "N" to "R".
- Contributions [folder 6 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Correspondence from organizations listed alphabetically "S" to "Z".
- Contributions [folder 7 of 7], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Contributions list from July to December.
- Car Rental, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Correspondence and memorandums regarding accidents, repairs, and car preference. It also includes a brochure.
- City of Hope, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 1 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 2 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous "C" [folder 3 of 3], 1971 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Columbia University, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Correspondence about a proposed labor seminar.
- Contributions Denied [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Proposals and pamphlets from organizations requesting for contributions.
- Contributions Denied [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Created Space, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Drafts, notices, memorandums, and correspondence.
- Clothing Negotiation, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Notices, memorandums, agreements, and correspondence.
- Complaints A-M, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Complaints N-Z, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Target Sportswear, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Correspondence and a 1972 clothing magazine called "Clothes".
- Threatening Letters, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Two angry, personal handwritten letters to Mr. Potofsky.
- Urban Community Insurance Company [folder 1 of 2], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Agendas, exhibits, correspondence, and financial statements.
- Urban Community Insurance Company [folder 2 of 2], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Urban Community Insurance Company - Outline for Homeowners Program, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Policy provisions and documents for customers regarding the insurance.
- Van Heusen [folder 1 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Various documents including election results, memos, reports, and newspaper clippings.
- Van Heusen [folder 2 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Van Heusen [folder 3 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Various documents including election results, memos, reports, pamphlets, and newspaper clippings.
- Van Heusen [folder 4 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Van Heusen [folder 5 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Elmer L. Ward, Senior Dinner, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  October 30. Invitations, correspondence, a list of contacts, a few pamphlets from the invites.
- National Committee for Full Employment [folder 1 of 5], 1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  A draft bill, a summaries of amendments to Equal Opportunity and Full Employment Act, statements of purpose, correspondence, pamphlets, and memos.
- National Committee for Full Employment [folder 2 of 5], 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Correspondence, summaries of the Equal Opportunity and Full Employment Act, and memorandums.
- National Committee for Full Employment [folder 3 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  Correspondence including a telegram from Mrs. Martin Luther King, Jr., reports, newspaper clippings, United States Conference of Mayors attendance list and handwritten notes.
- National Committee for Full Employment [folder 4 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  Correspondence and memorandums.
- National Committee for Full Employment [folder 5 of 5], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Reports, handwritten notes, and correspondence.